<?xml version="1.0"?>
<block>
  <name>M-PSK Ambiguity Resolver with Softbits (CCSDS)</name>
  <key>ccsds_mpsk_ambiguity_resolver_f</key>
  <category>CCSDS/Receiver/Synchronization</category>
  <import>import ccsds</import>
  <import>import math</import>
  <make>ccsds.mpsk_ambiguity_resolver_f($M,$ASM,$ASM_len,$threshold,$corr_threshold,$frame_len,$num_tail_sym)</make>
	<param>
		<name>M</name>
		<key>M</key>
		<value>8</value>
		<type>int</type>
	</param>
	<param>
		<name>Sync Marker (hex)</name>
		<key>ASM</key>
		<value>'1ACFFC1D'</value>
		<type>string</type>
	</param>
	<param>
		<name>ASM length</name>
		<key>ASM_len</key>
		<value>32</value>
		<type>int</type>
	</param>
	<param>
		<name>Lock threshold</name>
		<key>threshold</key>
		<value>1</value>
		<type>int</type>
	</param>
	<param>
		<name>Correlation threshold</name>
		<key>corr_threshold</key>
		<value>0.8</value>
		<type>real</type>
	</param>
	<param>
		<name>Frame data length</name>
		<key>frame_len</key>
		<type>int</type>
	</param>
	<param>
		<name>Tail length</name>
		<key>num_tail_sym</key>
		<value>0</value>
		<type>int</type>
	</param>
	<check>$M >= 2</check>
	<check>len($ASM) != 0</check>
	<check>$ASM_len > 0</check>
	<check>math.ceil($ASM_len/8.0) == len($ASM)/2</check>
	<check>$threshold > 0</check>
	<check>$corr_threshold > 0.0</check>
	<check>$corr_threshold &lt;= 1.0</check>
	<check>$frame_len > 0</check>
	<check>$num_tail_sym >= 0</check>
	<sink>
		<name>in</name>
		<type>float</type>
	</sink>
	<source>
		<name>out</name>
		<type>message</type>	
	</source>
	<doc>
M-PSK soft bit ambiguity resolver including Frame and Node synchronization.

Take the softbits of an M-PSK detector (with bit ambiguity) and look for the
attatched sync marker (ASM) in each possible ambiguity stream of the input,
including the original input. Once the ASM is found, lock on the stream
with tha ambiguity containing the ASM and look for the following ASMs. If in
fully locked state a threshold number of ASM can be missing until the block
enters search mode again.

M: Number of modulation symbols.

Sync Marker: Hexadecimal representation of the ASM. Must be of odd length as the
ASM must be an integer number of bytes.

Lock threshold: Everytime an ASM is found a counter is increased up to this
threshold value. Everytime a ASM is expected, but did not match the counter is
decreased. As long as the counter is larger than zero the block is in locked
state, returning the bytes of the locked stream as output. If the counter
reaches zero the block enters search mode again and stops it's output until it
is locked again. Setting threshold to one will make the block loose lock
immediatley if an exprected ASM does not match.

Correlation threshold: Threshold for the normalized correlation between ASM and
stream to consider both matching. A value of 1.0 means that every softbit must
match the ASM and have highest confidence, while 0.0 means that even a sequence
of erasures is considered as the ASM.

Frame data length: Length of the frame data (excluding the ASM) in bytes. Every
frame data length after an ASM another ASM is expected.
	</doc>
</block>
